Shrikanth Narayanaswamy Chandrasekaran

website: https://snaraya7.github.io/ e-mail: snaraya7@ncsu.edu

RESEARCH (Research Assistant, North Carolina State University) 2017 to present

Interest: Software Engineering, Machine Learning, and Human-Computer Interaction

Focus area: Software Quality Assurance | Lab: RAISE(http://ai4se.net/) Advisor: Dr.Tim Menzies (http://menzies.us/)

Our recent empirical study confirms that "96% of the time, we do not want and we do not need data-hungry methods" (refer publication [1] below).

OTHER RESEARCH AREAS: Code Retrieval, Crowdsourcing, Test case prioritization and Software Maintenance.

EDUCATION

2017 - Pursuing a **PhD in Computer Science** at North Carolina State University (Expected graduation - May 2022)

2004 – 2008 : 4 year full-time Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication, Saveetha Engineering College, affiliated to Anna University – Chennai

SKILLS

- * Programming: Java (SCJP and SCWCD certified) & Python. Fundamentals: Data Structures, Algorithms & Compilers
- ❖ Statistics: Hypotheses testing, effect size, analysis of distributions etc
- ❖ *Machine Learning:* Predictive/Estimate modelling, Weka data mining, scikit, Deep learning (Tensorflow,CNN & RNN) Carrot2, ELK and OPEN NLP. *Visualization:* Plotly, MATLAB, R etc.
- * Front-End: Java Swing, Eclipse Plugin development and HTML-CSS. Database: RDBMS (MySQL & MariaDB).
- ❖ Distributed computing: Python multiprocessing on High Performance computing

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. N. C. Shrikanth, Suvodeep Majumder, and Tim Menzies. Early Life Cycle Software Defect Prediction. Why? How? (To appear in ICSE '21).
- 2. N. C. Shrikanth, William Nichols, Fahmid Morshed Fahid, and Tim Menzies. Assessing Practitioner Beliefs about Software Engineering. (To appear in EMSE '21 Journal).
- 3. N. C. Shrikanth, and Tim Menzies. 2020. Assessing Practitioner Beliefs about Software Defect Prediction. (ICSE '20 SEIP) ? (Best Paper Nominee).
- **4.** Anurag Dwarakanath, **N. C. Shrikanth**, Kumar Abhinav, and Alex Kass. 2016. Trustworthiness in enterprise crowdsourcing: a taxonomy & evidence from data . (**ICSE** '16 SEIP).
- 5. Anurag Dwarakanath, Upendra Chintala, **Shrikanth N. C.**, Gurdeep Virdi, Alex Kass, Anitha Chandran, Shubhashis Sengupta, and Sanjoy Paul. 2015. CrowdBuild: a methodology for enterprise software development using crowdsourcing (CSI-SE ICSE '15).

GRANTED PATENTS

- 1. Method and system for visual requirements and component reuse driven rapid application composition
- 2. Incident Prediction and Prevention
- 3. Generating a Test Script Execution Order

INDUSTRY EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Summer 2020 Fujitsu Laboratories of America, USA

Role: Research Intern

Shrikanth Narayanaswamy Chandrasekaran

website: https://snaraya7.github.io/ e-mail: snaraya7@ncsu.edu

Low code platform: Improved deep learning based 'Code Retrieval' models (using CodeBERT & CodeSearchNet) that catalyze developer productivity.

2014 – 2017 Accenture Labs, India

Role: Technology R&D Specialist

- Analyzed obstacles for enterprises to crowdsource software development
- Analyzed voluminous incident tickets and their associated log files of a supermarket chain to prescribe solutions to minimize incident resolution time.
- Recognized for outstanding contributions

2011 – 2014 ABB India Limited, Bangalore India

Role: Software Engineer | Software Development, LV Systems R&D

- Developed a standalone Low voltage switchgear configuration and reporting tool predominantly based on Java.
- Star Employee for a quarter

2008 – 2011 Infosys Limited, Chennai India

Role: Senior Systems Engineer

- Built user interface rich integration tools that ease software developers to orchestrate banking services.
- Finacle on the spot award

TALKS

- ❖ ICSE'20 Assessing Practitioner Beliefs about Software Defect Prediction https://youtu.be/UokXMoP-v7O?t=2094
- ❖ ICSE'20 What Disconnects Practitioner Belief and Empirical Evidence https://youtu.be/UbuG6UwVzuU